imjane@umich.edu
https://github.com/tru

https://github.com/trusttri

https://imjane.net

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor Computer Science & Engineering School of Information

#### **Research Interests**

Social Computing, Human-Computer Interaction, Consent, Privacy, Digital Safety

I'm interested in tackling various integrity issues on social media, such as online harassment, surveillance, and misinformation. I focus on the relationship between such problems and users' consent, and research how consent can be better incorporated into platform design. Specifically, I combine empirical methods, system-building approaches, and theoretical work to improve social systems' privacy features, safety and governance tools, and business models.

### **Education**

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Ph.D. in Information & Computer Science and Engineering

Advisors: Florian Schaub (Information), Nikola Banovic (CSE)

School of Information & Division of Computer Science and Engineering, College of Engineering

(As the only PhD student, I assisted CSE and SI faculty in drafting a proposal to aid students that want to pursue a PhD in both programs via the Student Initiated Doctoral Program (SIDP).)

GPA: 3.85/4.0

Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

B.B.A. in Business Administration

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering

GPA: 4.29/4.50

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA

Undergraduate special student program (non-degree, full-time enrollment)

GPA: 4.8/5.0

## **Employment**

Meta, Menlo Park, CA (remote)

June 2021 - Aug. 2021

User Experience Research Intern for Facebook with Scarlett Sheng

Sassafras Tech Collective, Ann Arbor, MI (remote)

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

Sept. 2018 - Present

Sept. 2018 - current

Mar. 2013 - Aug. 2018

Sept. 2016 - May 2017

Software Development & Research Intern with Jill Dimond

Airbnb, San Francisco, CA

Research Intern Recipient 2020, Internship deferred due to COVID-19

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Research Assistant, Teaching Assistant

#### **Awards and Honors**

#### Selected to attend Human Computer Interaction Consortium (HCIC)

2022

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

One of three UMich PhD students selected to attend Human Computer Interaction Consortium (HCIC). Declined.

Barbour Scholar 2022-2023

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Provides one year of funding to "students working on dissertations that are unusually creative, ambitious, and impactful" who are women from Asia or the Middle East.

#### Finalist for Meta PhD Research Fellowship

2022

Meta, Menlo Park, CA

Finalist under Privacy and Data Use

#### **Best Paper Honorable Mention Award**

2021

ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2021) [c3]

#### Best Paper Runner Up Award

2020

ACM Conference on Web Science (WebSci 2020) [c4]

#### 2017 Annual Soft Robotics Competitions 1st prize in Design

2017

Harvard University, Cambridge, MA

#### Big Data Analytics Competition 3rd Prize

2015

SK Telecom, Seoul, Republic of Korea

### Korea University Honor Scholarships

2014 spring & fall, 2015 fall

Korea University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

Honors Scholarships, 33% of tuition covered for 2014 spring, 50% of tuition covered for 2015 fall

Best Honors Scholarships, tuition fully covered for 2014 fall

## **Publications**

## Proceedings and Journals

[c1] Hariharan Subramonyam, Jane Im, Colleen Seifert, Eytan Adar. Solving Separation-of-Concerns Problems in Collaborative Design of Human-AI Systems through Leaky Abstractions. *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2022)*. 24.7% *Acceptance Rate* 

https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3491102.3517537

[c2] Jane Im, Sarita Schoenebeck, Marilyn Iriarte, Gabriel Grill, Daricia Wilkinson, Amna Batool, Rahaf Alharbi, Audrey N. Funwie, Tergel Gankhuu, Eric Gilbert, Mustafa Naseem. Beyond Borders: Women's Perspectives on Harm and Justice after Online Harassment. ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW 2022). recommended for acceptance.

[c3] Jane Im, Jill Dimond, Melody Berton, Una Lee, Katherine Mustelier, Mark Ackerman, Eric Gilbert. Yes: Affirmative Consent as a Theoretical Framework for Understanding and Imagining Social Platforms. *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2021)*. Yokohama, Japan. April 2021. 26.3% *Acceptance Rate* [project website] Best Paper Honorable Mention Award

https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445778

[c4] Jane Im, Eshwar Chandrasekharan, Jackson Sargent, Paige Lighthammer, Taylor Denby, Ankit Bhargava, Libby Hemphill, David Jurgens, Eric Gilbert. Still Out There: Modeling and Identifying Russian Troll Accounts on Twitter. *ACM Conference on Web Science (WebSci 2020)*. Southampton, UK. 27% *Acceptance Rate* Best Paper Runner Up Award https://doi.org/10.1145/3394231.3397889

[c5] Jane Im, Sonali Tandon, Eshwar Chandrasekharan, Taylor Denby, Eric Gilbert. Synthesized Social Signals: Computationally-Derived Social Signals from Account Histories. *ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2020)*. Honolulu, HI. April 2020. 24.3% *Acceptance Rate* 

https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376383

[c6] Jane Im, Amy X. Zhang, Christopher J. Schlling, David Karger. Deliberation and Resolution on Wikipedia: A Case Study of Request for Comments. *ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW 2018)*. New York, NY. November 2018. 25% *Acceptance Rate* https://doi.org/10.1145/3274343

[c7] Jane Im, Paul Medlock-Walton, Mike Tissenbaum. App Inventor VR Editor for Computational Thinking. *Computational Thinking in Education Conference (CTE 2017)*. Hong Kong. June 2017. https://www.eduhk.hk/cte2017/doc/CTE2017%20Proceedings.pdfpage=171

## Papers under submission

[c8] Paul Resnick, Aljohara Alfayez, Jane Im, Eric Gilbert. Informed Crowds Can Effectively Identify Misinformation https://arxiv.org/pdf/2108.07898.pdf

### **Book Chapters**

[b1] Una Lee, Dann Toliver, Tawana Petty, Jane Im, Boaz Sender. Building Consentful Tech. Feminist Designer. Ed. Ali Place, MIT Press. Forthcoming 2023.

### Workshop Papers

[w1] Sarita Schoenebeck, Jane Im, Amna Batool, Daricia Wilkinson, Audrey Funwie, Rahaf Alharbi, Marilyn Iriarte, Gabriel Grill, Eric Gilbert, Mustafa Naseem. Repairing Online Harms: Assessing Punitive and Reparative Justice Approaches. First Annual Conference of The Platform Governance Research Network. March 2021.

[w2] Jane Im, Jeeyoon Hyun, Jill Dimond, Melody Berton, Eric Gilbert. Building Social Platforms around Affirmative Consent. Moving Forward Together: Effective Activism For Change Workshop at ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2020). Honolulu, HI. April 2020.

[w3] Jane Im. Non-consensual Images & Videos and Consent in Social Media. Sensitive Research, Practice, and Design in HCI Workshop at ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI 2019). Glasgow, UK. May 2019.

#### Media Publication

[m1] Heeryung Choi, Jane Im, Cindy Lin, Yixin Zou. An open letter to the U-M community. *The Michigan Daily*. https://www.michigandaily.com/opinion/op-eds/an-open-letter-to-the-u-m-community/ *I co-wrote an op-ed on anti-Asian racism in the U.S. (and academia)*.

## Research Experience

Facebook

June 2021 - Aug. 2021

User Experience Research Intern, advised by Scarlett Sheng (other mentors: Rui Yang & Ayesha Zafar)

- Impacted Facebook's privacy strategy by doing foundational mixed-method research to understand users' perception of consent in the context of online behavioral advertising and App Tracking Transparency.
- Quantitatively analyzed existing survey data to understand Facebook advertisers' goals.

#### Sassafras Tech Collective

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

Software Development & Research Intern, advised by Jill Dimond

- Built and conducted (remote) usability testing of a moderation system.
- Based on the usability testing results, designed mockups and further developed the moderation system.

University of Michigan

Sept. 2018 - Present

Research Assistant

• Currently researching how to design and build novel privacy and consent mechanisms that protect people's safety and agency in user-to-system and user-to-user interactions.

- Using social science theories, system-building, interviews, and surveys, uncovered how lack of consent can lead to a wide range of problems on social media, with users wanting fine-grained and usable privacy and safety tools [c<sub>3</sub>, c<sub>5</sub>].
- Built ML models to identify potential Russian trolls on Twitter, using an unbalanced dataset of 2.2K Russian troll accounts released by Twitter and 170K control accounts [c4].

#### Haystack Group, MIT

Apr. 2017 - Apr. 2018

Undergraduate Research, advised by Amy X. Zhang and David Karger

• Investigated how various factors affect the outcome of Request for Comments (RfC), a deliberative discussion on Wikipedia, by using mixed methods: 1) interviewing Wikipedia editors and 2) creating and quantitatively analyzing an English RfC dataset [c6].

#### MIT App Inventor, MIT

Oct. 2016 - May 2017

Undergraduate Research, advised by Paul Medlock-Walton and Hal Abelson

- Enabled novice programmers to create modular code in the App Inventor, by developing customized blocks within the system that can execute any functions of an imported API.
- Implemented virtual reality (VR) blocks in the App Inventor to help novice users build VR apps [c7].

#### Soft Active Materials Lab, MIT

Sept. 2016 - Feb. 2017

Undergraduate Research, advised by Hyunwoo Yuk

- Developed 3D printing based soft robotic hands with stand-alone actuation and control system.
- Implemented the software interface for precise 3D printing for advanced soft materials.

Deliberation and Resolution on Wikipedia: A Case Study of Requests for Comments

### **Invited Talks and Guest Lectures**

[t1] Invited talk at Expertise@Scale Lab, Carnegie Mellon University Designing and Building Social Platforms Grounded in Consent	Mar. 2022
[t2] DUB Shorts Seminar, University of Washington Yes: Affirmative Consent as a Theoretical Framework for Understanding and Imagining Social Platforms	Aug. 2021 s
[t <sub>3</sub> ] MetaGov Seminar, Metagovernance Project Reimagining and Building Social Platforms Grounded in Consent	Apr. 2021
[t4] HCI Seminar, Seoul National University Reimagining and Building Social Platforms Grounded in Consent	Jan. 2021
[t5] CS 598 Antisocial Computing Guest Lecture, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Building Social Platforms Grounded in Consent	Oct. 2020
[t6] EECS 598 Human-Computer Interaction Guest Presentation, University of Michigan Synthesized Social Signals: Computationally-Derived Social Signals from Account Histories	Apr. 2020
[t7] PhD Recruitment Flash Talk, University of Michigan School of Information Still Out There: Modeling and Identifying Russian Troll Accounts on Twitter	Feb. 2019
[t8] Wikimedia Showcase, Wikimedia Foundation Deliberation and Resolution on Wikipedia: A Case Study of Requests for Comments	Sept. 2018
[t9] IAR Seminar, University of Michigan School of Information	Sept. 2018

## **Press**

Quoted in Privacy by Design laws will kill your data pipelines.

Protocol. Hirsh Chitkara. May 16, 2022.

Jane Im awarded Rackham Barbour Scholarship.

University of Michigan CSE News. Mar. 25, 2022.

Predictive Model Identifies Wikipedia Arguments that Will Never Get Resolved.

Campus Technology. Dian Schaffhauser. Nov 27, 2018.

A Third of Wikipedia Discussions Are Stuck in Forever Beefs.

Vice Motherboard. Samantha Cole. Nov 7, 2018.

## **Teaching Experience**

## SI 539: Web Design, Development, and Accessibility, University of Michigan

Winter 2020

Graduate Student Instructor

- A graduate course providing hands-on approach to learning responsive, accessible front-end programming for Web Design. Topics covered include HTML5, CSS3 (including Bootstrap framework), JavaScript, and the POUR design principles of accessible design.
- Led 2 discussion sections per week.

## SI 339: Web Design, Development, and Accessibility, University of Michigan

Awarded the Blue Ribbon Certificate for his presentation at the UROP symposium.

Fall 2019

Graduate Student Instructor

• An undergraduate version of the course above.

## **Academic Mentoring**

Paige Lighthammer, University of Michigan Nuclear Engineering (Undergraduate) [c	4] Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019	
Jackson Sargent, University of Michigan CSE (Undergraduate) [c4]	Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019	
Ankit Bhargava, University of Michigan CSE (Undergraduate) [c4]	Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019	
Taylor Denby, University of Michigan Cognitive Science (Undergraduate) [c4, c5] Next: University of Michigan School of Information, Masters	Sept. 2018 - Aug. 2019	
Sonali Tandon, University of Michigan School of Information (Masters) [c5]	Sept. 2018 - Apr. 2019	
Katherine Mustelier, University of Michigan School of Information (Undergraduate)	[c3] Mar. 2020 - May. 2020	
Evan Wang, University of Michigan Computer Science (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2020	
Jake Klaristenfeld, University of Michigan CSE (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2020 - Apr. 2021	
Eleanor Desmond, University of Michigan Electrical Engineering (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2020 - July 2021	
Jolie Kaplan, University of Michigan CSE (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2020 - July 2021	
Alice Li Wang, University of Michigan Stephen M. Ross School of Business & School of Information (Undergraduate)	Feb. 2021 - Apr. 2021	
Annie Chen, University of Michigan Computer Science (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2020 - Present	
Ruiyi Yang, University of Michigan CSE (Undergraduate)	Oct. 2021 - Present	
Weikun Lyu, University of Michigan Math & CS (Undergraduate)  Oct. 2020 - Apr. 2021; Jan. 2022 - Present		

## Service

Review

 UIST
 2022

 IEEE Pervasive Computing
 2022

 ACM CHI
 2021 - 2022

 ICWSM
 2022

 PLoS ONE
 2021

 ACM CSCW
 2019 - 2021

Leadership

**IEE ICDM** 

UMSI PhD Student Internship Information Session, Organizer

Fall 2021

2019

Organized a panel to give junior PhD students advice on finding and securing internships.

SI & CSE Student Initiated Doctoral Program (SIDP) Design, Assistant to faculty

Fall 2020

- Assisted faculty members in drafting a proposal for evaluating students that want to pursue a PhD in both SI and CSE. Led the effort as the only PhD student.
- I was told that I may be the first PhD student to be *formally evaluated* by SI and CSE PhD program committees and enrolled in the two programs via U-M's Student Initiated Doctoral Program (SIDP).

Michigan Interactive and Social Computing (MISC), Student Organizer

Fall 2020 - Winter 2021

Co-organized speaker series on HCI and social computing.

Doctoral Executive Committee (DEC)

Fall 2019 - Winter 2020

- DEC is a group of PhD students that represent the voice of PhD students at University of Michigan's School of Information.
- Organized social events and actively participated in addressing departmental issues that impact PhD students.

### Skills

Programming Languages. Python, C, Java, Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, SQL Research Methods. Interview, System building & User study, Usability testing, Survey, Machine Learning Web framework. Django, Flask, Ruby on Rails Software. GitHub, LATEX, Linux command line

#### Coursework

Ph.D. courses

Computer & Network Security, Technologies to Optimize Human Learning, Microarchitecture, Human-AI Interaction, Data Mining, Doctoral Foundations Seminar, Human-Computer Interaction, Qualitative Research Methods, Interpretivist Theories in Computer-Supported Cooperative Work/Social Computing, Research Methods

Computer Science & Math undergraduate courses

Programming Language, Data Structure, Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Data Communications, Probability and Random Process, Calculus with Lab I, Computer Programming I, Introduction to Linear Algebra, Operating Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Embedded Systems, Internet Protocols, Discrete Mathematics, Theory of Computation, Advanced Computer Programming & Lab, Project for Graduation, Introduction to Inference, User Interface Design, Intelligent Multimodal User Interfaces

Last updated: June 11, 2022